let's discuss the solution to our latest
amdas law quiz we have three possible
improvements and now we can use amdas
law to tell us which one of them is the
best for improving the branch CPI this
is our option one the overall speed up
is branches are happening 20% of the
time so so this is actually the
percentage of time so we can apply onel
law properly so the unaffected execution
time is 80% and the 20% we do affect we
speed up by how much by a factor of 4
over3 so this is
1.33 and we get a overall speed up of
1.05 the clock frequency increase from 2
to 3.3 GHz is affecting all of the
execution time so we can just compute
the speed up of this but for the sake of
exercise let's apply andle's law 1 minus
fraction enhanced is zero cuz everything
is enhanced the fraction enhanced is one
and the speed up we get here by going
from 2 to 2.3 GHz is 2.3 / 2 which is
1.15 and the overall speed up we get is
the
1.15 the third option is for stores the
unaffected fraction is 0.9 the affected
fraction is 0.1 the speed up of going
from 3 to two is 1.5 and when we compute
that
we get 1.34 so it's a very small speed
up even smaller than we got for branches
so overall improving the clock frequency
gives us a significantly higher
Improvement overall than the other two
options primarily because this is a
smaller Improvement in terms of speed up
on the fraction affected but the clock
frequency increase affects all of the
instructions versus here we affect only
20% % of the execution time and here we
are affecting only 10% of the execution
time